Dhruv Chandel, PhD

Senior Mechatronics Engineer

+91-7042367999 | dhruvchandel@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/dhruvchandel



PROFILE

Senior Mechatronics Engineer with over ten years of experience in Systems Modeling & Control, AI & Robotics, including three years in a leadership role with a global engineering software company. Looking to transition to an R&D role in Mechatronics/Robotics system development.

Key Skills:

- Engineering software development with MATLAB, Simulink, Python, C++, ROS, and Git.
- Research experience with power electronics, embedded hardware (ARM/Linux), motor control, battery management systems (BMS), and Hardware-in-the-Loop (HiL) testing.
- Experience with applying Machine Learning and Deep Learning to engineering problems.
- Collaborative team player, focused on growth and strategic impact.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MathWorks – Developers of MATLAB & Simulink Senior Team Lead, Education & Research

New Delhi, India 2022 – Present

- Managing a team of 4 Application Engineers in North & West India.
- Leading Technical Engagements in Electric Vehicles, Robotics & Autonomous Systems, Machine Learning and Computer Vision.
- Impact: 50% business growth over 3 years (over 100,000 new customers).

Senior Application Engineer – Education & Research

2019 – 2022

- Supported over 200 engineering institutes across India with integrating Computational Tools in curriculum & research.
- Led an internal project on Parallel Computing to ramp up over 30 engineers on using AWS with MATLAB, which is now the worldwide standard workflow.
- Successfully led a worldwide project to enable over 50 research groups to use MATLAB & Simulink Toolboxes for Robotic Systems Development.
- Awarded 'APAC Engineer of the Year' in 2021, out of 20 peers.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Mechanical Engineering (Renewable Energy) University of Bath

Bath, UK 2015 – 2018

Industry-partnered project on developing a Fault Tolerant Control system for a prototype renewable Wave Energy device.

MEng. Mechanical Engineering (1st Class Hons) University of Bath

Bath, UK 2011 – 2015

Specialization: Advanced Controls (MPC), Robotics, Computer Vision (OpenCV/C++)

Nationality: Indian | Languages: English, Hindi